SandeepVenkateshwar



FULL-STACK DATA SCIENTIST SOFTWARE ENGINEER DoB: 19/05/1990 Located in Antibes, France

Contact

+33 7 82 62 39 36 📞

skumarv.github.io

skumary o

skumarv7in

vsandeepkmr@gmail.com

■

Languages

English - Proficient French - Elementary (DELF A2 certifié) Tamil - Mother Tongue Hindi - Advanced

Resume

With 9.6 years of IT experience, I attain a wide spectrum of knowledge and experiences in data analysis, statistics and machine learning for engineering. My key strengths are also a good sense of data and its interpretations, a mindset of problem-solving and analytical thinking. Collaborations among different fields sharpen my capability to work in team, communicate and vulgarize complex problems

Experience

2018 - Now **Data Scientist - Amadeus**

Sophia-Antipolis, Nice, France

AUSY

- Machine Learning in Hadoop on streaming data up to 150K TPS.
- Key Performance Indicators(KPI) generation by doing data transformations, matching & aggregations using Spark.
- · Data exploration & Data science using conda.
- Develop generic Angular UI to create, monitor & get alerts for KPIs.
- · Working on Amadeus Cloud Services, AWS & Openshift.

2017 - 2018 **Oracle ERP Consultant - Aubert & Duval**

Clermont-Ferrand, France

Logelis

• Migration to Oracle ERP Cloud using Oracle SOA suite connectors from various Enterprise Resource Planning softwares (Ex: SAS, Oracle EBusiness Suite, etc.).

2017 - 2017 **BigData Engineer - Suntrust Bank** IBM

Hyderabad, India

Hyderabad, India

• Data Lake creation on Hive using Cloudera tools.

- Petabytes of data from 800 different sources are flattened from Avro to parquet formats for Data science & Machine learning requirements.
- Data correction, alteration and schema evaluation are some common checks done during the process.

2016 - 2017 **Analyst Programmer - Mapfre Insurance**

IBM

Automation of insurance renewals and other tech-control using PL/SQL.

• Develop front-end interfaces to manage policies using Spring Webflow, Javascript, HTML & CSS.

2012 - 2016 **Senior Software Engineer - Credit Suisse Bank** Pune, India & Canary Wharf, London, UK Wipro

- Lead and co-ordinate multiple software releases between teams across London, Wrocław & Pune(India).
- Implemented Master Data Management system(EBX5) to maintain golden source of information distribute to downstream systems.
- Read, validate, transform and match data in batches by applying business rules and ISDA regulatory checks.

2010 - 2012 **Software Engineer - Citibank**

Pune, India

Wipro

- Oracle ADF application developed for smart data entry platform.
- Data validation and checks are served using Oracle OPA business rules engine.
- · SOAP webservices were used to read and store data in Oracle Siebel(Server & Database).

Education

2011 - 2014	Birla Institute of Technology and Science (BITS) Master's Degree - Software Engineering, 6.3 CGPA	Pilani, India
2007 - 2010	Loyola Academy (Autonomous and affiliated to Osmania University) Se Bachelor's Degree - Computer Science and Engineering, 67%	ecunderabad, India
2005 - 2007	Board of Higher Secondary Education - Math, Physics & Chemistry Higher Secondary Certificate, 65%	Hyderabad, India
2005	Board of Secondary Education Secondary High School, 75.6%	Hyderabad, India

Notable Project

2020 Minutely & Daily KPIs streamed into Elasticsearch Project in Amadeus

Using KafkaConnect, stats are fed to Elasticsearch and HDFS(for backup & extraction of new KPIs). Traffic is monitored using Kibana & Grafana dashboards. Kibana is used to create visualization charts like timeseries, pie, logs etc. while Grafana provided cluster monitoring capabilities like number of shards, indexes, documents per each node etc.

2019 Data Science with pyspark & other conda libs

Project in Amadeus

Week on week trend prediction, ratio computation & various data science operations performed using pyspark, numpy, matpotlib, elasticsearch, etc,. and create dashboards to study trends

2017 Data Lake

Project in IBM

By customising databricks Avro to Parquet conversion libraries the data is read, transformed, flattenized and stored on Hive data warehouse with dynamic schema evolution capabilities. New columns in Hive are created automatically allowing user to read new and old data formats and is fully monitored and logged by HBase(NoSQL DB)

Skills

Tools

Eclipse, JetBrains, Visual Studio, Android Studio, JUnit Testing, Git, XAMP

· Industry Knowledge

Problem-solving, Cloud Computing, Formal Languages and Compilers, Metaheuristic Algorithm, Operating System, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Cryptography, Technical writing, Software development, Database Management (SQL, NoSQL), Unix

Languages

Java, Scala, Python, Bash, C++, SQL, JavaScript, Groovy

Architecture

Spark, Kafka, Openshift, Kubernetes, SOA, MVC, Webservices

· Web Technologies

Angular, Node, Jasmine, Karma, Selenium, HTML5, CSS

Databases

Elasticsearch, Couchbase, HBase, Hive, Avro, Protobuf, Parquet, MongoDB, Oracle, MySQL

· Libraries & Frameworks

Mapr, Cloudera, MapReduce, Spring, Spring-batch, Mockito, Junit, NumPy, Matplotlib, GIT, Maven, Sonar, Jenkins, Jfrog, PyPl, Conda, Docker, Yarn

Methodologies

Agile, TDD

· Soft Skills

Attention to detail, Teamwork & cooperation, Teaching, Time management

Extra Curricular Activities

· Coding Competition

Active player of online coding games (HackerRank) and participated to different hackathons.

Udemy courses

Followed courses concerning Convolutional Neural Networks, Natural Language Processing and Network Security (Nmap Ethical Hacking).

· Member of Machine Learning Group at IBM

Passionate Machine Learning tech co-workers working in various parts of the world with whom ideas and knowledge are exchanged. Gained knowledge in Machine Learning and Deep Learning area.